<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects I&#39;ve Authored or Worked On on Martin Musale</title>
    <link>https://musale.github.io/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects I&#39;ve Authored or Worked On on Martin Musale</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2021 Martin Musale</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://musale.github.io/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>HOYT Hugo Theme</title>
      <link>https://musale.github.io/projects/hoyt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://musale.github.io/projects/hoyt/</guid>
      <description>Motivation I bumped into Ben Hoyt&amp;rsquo;s website during my rounds on the internet. I liked the way the website is laid out. Since I have been looking for a proper layout for my personal website, I found the site to be exactly what I wanted. The reason I made it into a hugo theme is because I used it for my site and it would be good to have one of them themes.</description>
      <content>&lt;h2 id=&#34;motivation&#34;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bumped into &lt;a href=&#34;https://benhoyt.com/&#34;&gt;Ben Hoyt&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; website during my rounds on the internet. I liked the way the website is laid out. Since I have been looking for a proper layout for my personal website, I found the site to be exactly what I wanted. The reason I made it into a &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;hugo&lt;/a&gt; theme is because I used it for my site and it would be good to have one of them themes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;results&#34;&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I created a hugo theme named &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/musale/hoyt&#34;&gt;hoyt&lt;/a&gt; &lt;del&gt;for obvious reasons, d&amp;rsquo;uh&lt;/del&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s still a work in progress and contributions are welcome in accordance to the standard guidelines of contributing to OSS. I&amp;rsquo;m looking to add more features and hopefully make this into a fully-fledged theme but for the time being, my fingers are crossed.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing the Tessaract OCR Project</title>
      <link>https://musale.github.io/projects/txt-from-img/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://musale.github.io/projects/txt-from-img/</guid>
      <description>Motivation This was a pet project to test out OCR using the Tessaract project. We&amp;rsquo;re currently processing legal documents and some of them are in PDF or image formats. This necessitates an OCR solution which was a good place to start so that the process can be automated. Also, I was looking for a way to make lambda deployments easy and seamless. In the project, most of the setup has been done thanks to inspiration from already existing solutions.</description>
      <content>&lt;h2 id=&#34;motivation&#34;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a pet project to test out OCR using the Tessaract project. We&amp;rsquo;re currently processing legal documents and some of them are in PDF or image formats. This necessitates an OCR solution which was a good place to start so that the process can be automated. Also, I was looking for a way to make lambda deployments easy and seamless. In the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/musale/txt-from-img&#34;&gt;project&lt;/a&gt;, most of the setup has been done thanks to inspiration from already existing solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;results&#34;&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was able to deploy a lambda function which you can invoke by sending an image which will return the text in the image. Currently, only text in English language can be processed. Other options are possible but are not covered. You can clone the project and test it out on your machine or who knows, get it on one of your pipelines! Enjoy OCR. :camera:&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>M-Pesa AsyncIO</title>
      <link>https://musale.github.io/projects/aiompesa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://musale.github.io/projects/aiompesa/</guid>
      <description>Motivation The reason I wrote this library is because:
 I wanted to learn some more about asyncio. To create an asynchronous library. Experiment with Python 3+ static typing.  Results I understand a little more about asyncio and the various IO problems that it is trying to solve. Maybe you might not need to make async M-Pesa calls now in your product but, it&amp;rsquo;s something you can consider in future.</description>
      <content>&lt;h2 id=&#34;motivation&#34;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason I wrote this library is because:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wanted to learn some more about &lt;em&gt;asyncio&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To create an asynchronous library.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experiment with Python 3+ static typing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;results&#34;&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I understand a little more about &lt;em&gt;asyncio&lt;/em&gt; and the various IO problems that it is trying to solve. Maybe you might not need to make async M-Pesa calls now in your product but, it&amp;rsquo;s something you can consider in future. The &lt;em&gt;aiompesa&lt;/em&gt; library is available on &lt;em&gt;pypy&lt;/em&gt; and open sourced at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/musale/aiompesa&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. For more information on how to use it you can read about it&amp;rsquo;s usage &lt;a href=&#34;https://aiompesa.readthedocs.org&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and test it out. Cheers! :beer:&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
